is absolutely insane so today I would
like to give you a tiny introduction to
it and show you how you can run it on
your own computer LGBT is an open source
software project that is blowing up on
GitHub it was created just a month ago
and it's already in the top 100 GitHub
repositories with the most stars it was
placed 55 the last time I checked it
already has more than 90
000 Stars it's already above the Ross
programming language Django Tailwind
pytorch spring Boot and Bitcoin I mean
look at that graph absolutely explosive
growth so what is auto gbt I assume that
by this point we have all used charge
GPT at least once with chagibiti we are
all used to writing a prompt asking a
question and receiving an answer we then
repeat this process one prompt and time
until we get what we want it's like Ping
Pong the human is doing the Ping and
chagibiti is doing the punk what
orogivity does is it removes the human
from the ping pong table it basically
allows the gpt4 model to write prompts
to itself all you have to do is give it
a task and auto gbt is going to come up
with the steps and prompts required to
accomplish the task all alone without
human intervention Auto GPT can
autonomously achieve the goals you set
for it the reason it can do this is
because Auto GPT is packed with many
awesome features it has internet access
it can search the web and gather
information required to complete a task
thanks to an integration with Vector
databases it has both long term and
short-term memory it uses gpt4 the
latest and most premium language model
when it needs to generate text and it
uses gpt3 and not so expensive but
faster language model when you need to
summarize files or websites it found on
the internet it can Google by itself it
can control your browser it can use
dally or stable diffusion if it needs to
generate images it can use the GitHub
and Twitter API and more it can also
write code and run it by itself and it
can also speak its progress out loud
using an AI voice service it is an
absolute increase so let me show you how
to get this bad boy running in your
computer I'm also going to give you some
tips on how to use it better so you
don't waste time and money so stick on
to the end of the video to find out to
run auto GPT you need to have python 3.8
or later installed in your system as
well as vs code and git if you don't
have them you can install them by
downloading each one of them from their
website after you're done with the
installation open your console on the
terminal drag and drop the documents
folder and then run this command this
will bring the latest and stable version
of automity code from GitHub into your
computer then open vs code go to file
open folder and select the auto GPT
folder located on your documents on this
code click view then terminal and on
that newly opened terminal run this
command this will install all the
packages required for auto gbts to work
after that look for the dot EMV that
template and duplicate it on vs code
just do right click copy and then right
click paste rename the newly created
copy to just that EMV and now it's time
to get you some API Keys we first need
an open aik since Auto GPT uses both
lgbt4 and gpt3 go to your openai account
API key section and create a new API key
a paid account is required to complete
this step so you will need to enter your
credit card information copy the API key
you got from openai go to your dot EMV
file and set it as the value of the
openai key environment variable because
we need the AI to be able to search
using Google we also need to get an API
key from them to do this go to the
Google Cloud console and log in or
create a new account if you don't
already have one from there create a new
project by clicking on the select a
project drop down at the top of the page
and selecting a new project give your
project a name and you are good to go
now it's time to enable the custom
search API head to the apis and services
dashboard click enable apis and services
and search for custom search API click
on it and then click enable and you are
all set next you will need to get your
API key go to the credentials page and
click create credentials choose API key
copy the API key go to the dot EMB file
on your vs code and paste it on the
Google API key variable we are almost
done I promise next go to the custom
search engine page and click add set up
a new custom search engine and send
select search the entire web then go to
the overview page of your search engine
and copy the search engine ID copy the
ID go to the dot EMB file on your vs
code and paste it on the custom search
engine ID environment variable unless
you add a credit card to Google Cloud
you will get a hundred searches for free
per day if you add one you get 10 000.
LGBT integrates with more services you
can also set up the API keys for a
GitHub Twitter AI voice Services stable
diffusion as well as a supported memory
bucket if we don't configure any memory
backend such as redis Pinecone and
others the memory will be saved locally
on your computer to use local memory
create a file called autogpd that Json
on the root of your project and you are
good to go we're done with the setup
let's now use this thing on your vs code
terminal start Auto GPT by running this
command LGBT will welcome us and ask us
to name our AI in my case I will go for
tour guide AI then we have to give the
AI a role I will say that tour guide AI
is an AI design to research travel
destinations and write travel brochures
after that we have to write down the
goals of our AI I want the AI to ride a
travel brochure for Dubrovnik a gorgeous
Croatian town the first goal would be
research Dubrovnik as a travel
destination the second one find things
to do and places to eat third one using
the results make a travel brochure for
Dubrovnik and the last goal when you
finish terminate press enter twice and
we are off to the races as you can see
rgbt comes up with thoughts reasoning a
plan criticism and speak which is how
rgbt tells us what is going to do then
it comes up with a command it wants to
execute it wants to run the Google
command to search for Dubrovnik travel
destination when Auto gbt proposes a
command we always have the option to
agree to it we can and say no or we can
provide extra feedback which is
something we're going to see a little
bit later after we say we agree it
searches Google and finds some websites
and it chooses Lonely Planet as the
first website to browse as you can see
it also came up with a plan it will
browse the website save important
information to files and use the
information it gathers to accomplish in
the task on the criticism part we can
see it says it needs to be sure it's
gathering information from reliable
sources now we want to run the browse
website command and after we accept it
it opens a browser goes to that website
and extracts information from it after
the information is extracted rgbt is now
asking for authorization to start a new
agent like a minion and it's giving it a
task how cool is that it knows what
prompts it needs it knows how to write
the prompts to get what it wants and is
executing those prompts because by this
point I am tired of having to approve
every command I instead it right y-50
which means that I'm authorizing the
next 50 commands this is a very useful
setting but it can be a little bit
dangerous as we will see later as time
passes we can see all GPT getting the
answers it wants from its agents and
using commands like right to file to
taking notes of what it's finding out we
let it do its thing and it's going to
keep Googling browsing and taking notes
we can see the files it has created and
the note it took on the auto GPT
workspace folder and we can also take a
look at the auto gbt that Json files to
see the memory of the AI this file
contains the data the AI has found as
text and text embeddings which is how
the AI can read its notes thanks to the
memory of Auto GPD we can kill the
program and when we come back and start
it later we won't have to start from the
beginning it will instead ask us if we
want to continue so cool now I want to
tell you about the feedback command
because I found it very useful as you
can see here it is asking me for
permission to browse the Lonely Planet
website instead of saying yes or no I am
telling it to not use Lonely Planet and
use Trip Advisor instead and sure enough
it listens to the feedback and decides
to browse TripAdvisor instead incredible
after the brochure was ready I asked it
to put on a markdown file and this is
the output I got it did really well
right from the start we can see it is
actually written as a tourist brochure
it is recommending four things to do
with their descriptions and it's also
recommending some places to eat and is
describing them as well it is also
ending with thank you for considering
Dubrovnik as your next travel
destination we hope to see you soon I
hope you agree with me on thinking that
LGBT is super cool and now let me tell
you what the not so good part about Auto
gptr and the things you have to be
careful about the biggest thing is that
it can be expensive to run auto GPT uses
gpt4 and d53 GB 3 is very cost efficient
and fast and gpt4 is better at reasoning
and Consciousness but it's more than 10
times more expensive than gpt3 to save
money you can run auto GPT like this
this will use a gpt3 only so you will
save a bit of money as we saw before it
can be annoying to have to approve every
single command or LGBT wants to run so
we can pass a number like we saw before
or if you really trust the machine you
can run auto GPT on continuous mode this
will run auto GPT without user
authorization 100 automated this setting
really isn't recommended because the AI
might run commands that you would
normally not allow instead of using the
dash dash continuous I would recommend
to use the Y dash number command but
don't go too high on the number because
if you do that then you won't be able to
give any feedback to the AI in between
commands you will need to use the
feedback well especially when you are
using rgbt to do research sometimes it
just falls down on a rabbit hole and
keeps Googling and taking notes forever
researching more and more and more if
that happens you can use feedback and
send something like normal googly finish
with the information you have another
thing you have to keep in mind is that
this product is an experiment and it
makes mistakes so there will be cases
where you might get stuck it won't be
able to correct itself it might enter
into an infinite Loop and you will have
to restart it that will be fine but
remember that you are paying every time
that auto GPT thinks of a command or
evaluates an output or get your feedback
even though we are talking cents on the
dollar those tiny costs will add up
quickly to avoid spending lots of money
go to your open AI settings and set a
hard limit to cap and limit how much
money your account is allowed to spend I
strongly recommend you set limit before
you start don't let the AI drain your
credit card even though it is limited
even though it can be expensive and does
not perform perfectly at all tasks LGBT
feels powerful AI is at a moment like
computers were a long ago back when they
were huge machines and they weren't that
good the difference is that unlike
computers AI is moving at an incredible
speed it's been a month since rgbt is
out can you imagine where it would be in
five years now is your turn in the
comments to let me know what do you
think about Auto GPT are you impressed
or disappointed do you think it's cool
is it too over hype are you going to run
it in your machine I hope you found this
video useful and if you did please
consider leaving a like and subscribing
to the channel and don't forget that if
you want to learn things like JavaScript
python react react native gold dark
flutter among many many others for
absolutely free all you have to do is
click the link below to join any of our
many free courses that you can take
right now for absolutely free with me
click the link below and I will see you
there honors
see you on the next one bye
thank you